David Lee Guss photographs, 1967-1982
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
David Lee Guss photographs, 1967-1982
AZ 505
Photographs, 8x10, taken chiefly in Arizona from 1967 to 1982.
Guss, David Lee
.4 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
David Lee Guss is a free-lance photographer from Tucson, Arizona. A number of his photographs appeared in the motion picture The Border.
Organization
This collection is organized into two series:
Series I: Photographs, 1967-1982
Series II: Biographical Materials, Articles and Miscellaneous Material
Scope and Content Note
Photographs, 8x10, taken chiefly in Arizona from 1967 to 1982. Subjects include Tucson buildings, parades, and people; motion pictures filmed in Arizona; Native Americans in Arizona, including Apache, Yaqui, and Tohono O'Odham; scenes and people in U.S.-Mexico border towns, Tombstone, Ariz., and ghost towns in Arizona and New Mexico.
Access Terms
Extinct cities -- Arizona -- Photographs
Extinct cities -- New Mexico -- Photographs
Ghost towns -- Southwest, New -- Photographs
Indians of North America -- Arizona -- Photographs
Apache Indians -- Photographs
Yaqui Indians -- Photographs
Old Tucson (Ariz.) -- Photographs
Motion pictures -- Arizona -- Photographs
Cities and towns -- Mexican-American Border Region -- Photographs
Tucson (Ariz.) -- Social life and customs
Tombstone (Ariz.) -- Photographs
Photographs
Container List
- Series I: Photographs, 1967-1982
  - Tucson, 1967-1982
    - Jacob's House. December 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - El Conquistador Hotel. September 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - South Meyer Avenue in the rain. September 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - El Paso & Southwestern Railroad Park. September 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ore crusher, Jacob's Assay Office. June-July 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Light bulb, Jacob's Assay Office. June-July 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1958 Mexican distillery calendar, Jacob's Assay Office. June-July 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 2nd Annual Indian Wars Memorial Encampment, Fort Lowell. May 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Barry Sadler wearing Nazi hat. April 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Barry Sadler teaching his sons how to aim toy rifles. April 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Children dressed as nuns, Parada de los Ninos. May 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Child, steps at Armory Park. May 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Child watching Fiesta de los Vaqueros Rodeo. March 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Child in battered hat, Parada de los Ninos. April 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Child in traditional Mexican dress, Parada de los Ninos. 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 91-year-old preacher, Armory Park. March 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Johnny Gibson Barber Shop. October 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Amish, El Con. July 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Preacher and children, Armory Park. May 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Hispanic holy rollers, South Tucson. April 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Hispanic march protesting Vietnam War. April 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Hard hat march supporting Vietnam War. May 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Elaine Zimmerman (fourth from left among finalists), instant winner in Arizona lottery drawing in the Community Center. March 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Across the finishing line, Rillito Race Track. May 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Line of dogs, Greyhound Park, South Tucson. January 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Women with matching sunglasses and cigarettes, Fiesta de los Vaqueros Rodeo. March 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Thumb-sucking child with friend, Hispanic picnic, El Rio Park. November 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Artist Ted de Grazia (1909-1985), Gallery in the Sun. March 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Martin D. Smith, Jr., El Con. December 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Martin D. Smith, Jr., Fiesta de los Vaqueros Rodeo. March 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Martin D. Smith, Jr., under the stands, Fiesta de los Vaqueros Rodeo. March 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ruben Fixit Shop. May 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Johnny Gibson Health and Gym Equipment window display. May 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Theater, 1968-1978
    - Balloon girl, Gypsy, U of A Drama. August 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Orchestra pit, Gypsy, U of A Drama. August 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Ruth Snelgrove as Regina Giddens, The Little Foxes, U of A Drama. March 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Self portrait as William Marshall, The Little Foxes, U of A Drama. March 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Sandy Rosenthal, founder of Arizona Civic Theater, directing A Delicate Balance, old Santa Rita Hotel. February 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Motion Pictures, 1967-1980
    - Main Street, Old Tucson, Arizona. July 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - John Wayne, Rio Lobo set, Old Tucson, Arizona. May 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Lee Marvin, Monte Walsh set, Old Tucson, Arizona. July 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Angie Dickinson, Young Billy Young set, Old Tucson, Arizona. July-August 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Robert Mitchum, Young Billy Young set, Old Tucson, Arizona. July-August 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Children as extras, Dirty Dingus Magee set, Mescal, Arizona. March 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Two women as extras, Dirty Dingus Magee set, Mescal, Arizona. March 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The Over the Hill Gang, Andy Devine, Chill Wills, Walter Brennan, and Edgar Buchanan, Old Tucson, Arizona. January 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Leif Erickson, Cameron Mitchell and Mark Slade, High Chaparral set, Old Tucson, Arizona. January 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Horse-drawn trolleys, The Great White Hope set, Globe, Arizona. October 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Balloon man, The Great White Hope set, Globe, Arizona. October 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Anti-boxing demonstrators, The Great White Hope set, Globe, Arizona. October 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Anti-boxing demonstrators, The Great White Hope set, Globe, Arizona. October 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Extras and their shadows, The Great White Hope set, Globe, Arizona. October 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1872 steam locomotive Reno, depot, Old Tucson, Arizona. January 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Joe Kidd set, Old Tucson, Arizona. December 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Lone horse, Dirty Dingus Magee set, Mescal, Arizona. March 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Wagon wheel graveyard, backlot, Old Tucson, Arizona. July 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Horses kissing, Joe Kidd set, Old Tucson, Arizona. July 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Skeleton, backlot, Old Tucson, Arizona. November 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bush, Tom Horn set, Mescal, Arizona. November 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Storm clouds, Tom Horn set, Mescal, Arizona. November 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Dogs, mule team, Dirty Dingus Magee set, Mescal, Arizona. March 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Halation, Dirty Dingus Magee set, Mescal, Arizona. March 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Indians, 1969-1975
    - Apache grandmother and granddaughter, White River, Arizona. September 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Crow, Inter-Tribal Indian Rodeo, Gallup, New Mexico. August 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Apache elders clutching fence, White River, Arizona. September 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Apache child and toy horse, White River, Arizona. September 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Apache father and son on carousel, White River, Arizona. September 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Apaches saluting, 100th anniversary of Fort Apache, Arizona. May 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Yaqui pascola dancers, Gallery in the Sun, Tucson, Arizona. March 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Yaqui deer dancer, Gallery in the Sun, Tucson, Arizona. March 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Catholic church, Pisinemo, Arizona. May 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wagons and tree, near Cowlic, Arizona. July 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Papago cowboy and water hole, near Topawa, Arizona. November 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Contaminated water hole (charco) during the worst drought on the Papago Indian Reservation, near Sells, Arizona. June-July 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Papago cowboy thrown off bull, Sells, Arizona. September 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Apache cowboys in the mud at a rodeo, White River, Arizona. September 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Papago cowboy camp, chuck wagon, near Topawa, Arizona. November 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Lucky Dollar (Papago bar), South Tucson. April 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - United States/Mexico Border 1968-1980
    - Loncheria Junior, Naco, Sonora. May 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Children at wedding, Matamoros, Tamaulipas. July 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Children in fountain, Nuevo Laredo, Nuevo Leon. July 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Family, Rio Rico, Arizona. September 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Cinco de Mayo Parade, Nogales, Sonora. May 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Wall, gate and cloud, Juarez, Chihuahua. July 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Circus posters, Juarez, Chihuahua. September 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Clown, John A. Strong Circus, Bisbee, Arizona. May 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Family and animals, John A. Strong Circus, Bisbee, Arizona. May 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ticket booth, carnival, Naco, Sonora. May 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Children at the movies, Juarez, Chihuahua. July 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 100th anniversary parade, Nogales, Arizona. October 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Children and dog in alley, Nogales, Sonora. March 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bull ring and baseball signs, Nuevo Laredo, Nuevo Leon. July 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Glint, Nogales, Sonora (bull fighting). April 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Dying bull, Nogales, Sonora. July 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Empty bull ring, Nogales, Sonora. May 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "You will find it" store, Nuevo Laredo, Nuevo Leon. July 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Joyous girl in alley, Nogales, Sonora. March 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Brewery Gulch, Bisbee, Arizona. September 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Tombstone, Arizona, 1967-1981
    - Welcome to Helldorado. October 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Old time photo store. October 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Sheriff, reenactment of the gunfight at the O. K. Corral. October 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Dead body, reenactment of the gunfight at the O. K. Corral. October 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Holseter and baby carriage. October 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Wild women of the West, Belle Starr. October 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Wild women of the West, cigar. October 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 100-year-old Sid Wilson and stew pot; cowboy, rancher, stagecoach and wagon builder, former double for the first Wester movie star Bronco Billy Anderson, bronc rider with Buffalo Bill's Wild West Show (1900-1911) and restorer of the O. K. Corral, Pick 'Em Up Ranch. February 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Sid Wilson in shed, Pick 'Em Up Ranch. February 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 101-year-old Sid Wilson being interviewed by writer Carol Ann Bassett, Pick 'Em Up Ranch. April 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Funeral of 102-year-old Sid Wilson (1879-1981), Pick 'Em Up Ranch. October 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Building with wooden shingles. September 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - George Wallace for President supporter, Bird Cage Saloon. October 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Women, Wyatt Earp exhibit sign. October 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Women, Wells Fargo museum. October 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Shadows, Casino Saloon sign. October 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Moon, courthouse. October 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ghost Towns, 1967-1981
    - Overgrown railroad tracks, Carbon Timber Town, Wyoming. July 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Chevron gas station, Gleeson, Arizona. March 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Building and car, Mogollon, New Mexico. August 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Next gas 122 miles, Mogollon, New Mexico. August 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Saloon, Shakespeare, New Mexico. April 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Building with light strips, Madrid, New Mexico. September 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Get grub, Salome, Arizona. April 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Not for sale or rent, Dos Cabezos, Arizona. November 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ore cart, ladder, Johnson, Arizona. October 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Goats, building, White Oaks, New Mexico (favorite haunt of Billy the Kid). September 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Horse (rear of building in no. 10), White Oaks, New Mexico. April 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Severed automobile, Dos Cabezos, Arizona. November 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Main Street, Cabezon, New Mexico. April 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Stone buildings, Trementina, New Mexico. April 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bale of Hay Saloon, Virginia City, Montana. August 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Library, Montana Post, Virginia City, Montana. August 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Fatoff obesity cream, Virginia City, Montana. August 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Dark haired lady, Virginia City, Montana. August 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Cupid, Virginia City Montana. August 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Cameo lady, Connor Hotel, Jerome, Arizona. March 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Store window, Central City, Colorado. July 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Child's grave, Dawson, New Mexico. January 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Hay mow, Pearce, Arizona. October 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Overgrown trees, buildings, Mowry, Arizona. January 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Trees, shadows, building, Mowry, Arizona. October 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Pond, Jardine, Montana. August 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Dawn Lake Valley, New Mexico. February 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Dusk, Victor, Colorado. July 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, 1967-1979
    - Restrooms, Sentinel, Arizona. April 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Circus tent in the Safari Hotel parking lot at the auction of two of Adolph Hitler's Mercedes-Benz touring cars, bought for $153,000 and $93,000 respectively, Scottsdale, Arizona. January 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Service station/post office, Wagoner, Arizona. May 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Tumacacori Mission, Tumacacori, Arizona. April 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Self-portrait, Antlers Hotel, Victor, Colorado. July 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - First World Hot Air Balloon Championship, Albuquerque, New Mexico. February 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Midway, Arizona State Fair, Phoenix, Arizona. November 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Flower children, San Francisco, California. July 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Along the beach, San Francisco, California. July 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Along the beach, Big Surf, Tempe Arizona. April 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Conductor, steam engine, White Mountains Scenic Railroad, McNary, Arizona. August 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Casino Center in the rain, Las Vegas, Nevada. May 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Reflections, MGM Grand, Reno, Nevada. August 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - John Dane, international gunrunner, saboteur and mercenary, with a portion of his weapons collection, American Fork, Utah. October 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Cemetery, Dawson City, Yukon Territory, Canada. July 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series II: Biographical Materials, Articles and Miscellaneous Material
  - Curriculum vitae. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Autobiographical essay tracing David Lee Guss' interest and activities in film. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - List of exhibitions, motion picture screenings, television shows. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Promotional brochure. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Article on David Lee Guss from La Voz del Norte, Nogales, Sonora, (in Spanish). February 8, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The Border (motion picture): Programs, news releases, letters, certificates relating to the motion picture. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 16 articles illustrated with photographs by David Lee Guss. 1971-1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Flyers, posters and programs illustrated with photographs by David Lee Guss. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 5 articles illustrated with photographs by David Lee Guss. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Shot in Arizona: A History of the Arizona Movie Industry." Story by Carol Bassett, photos by David Lee Guss. Tucson Weekly News, pp. 7-11. December 17-December 23, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 3 posters for a workshop on color photography in which David Lee Guss participated. (Box 2, Folder 6)